

# Claudio Cesar de Sá

Curriculum Vitae

# **SELF PRESENTATION**

I am a retired professor of Computer Science in Brazil after teaching for more than 35 years courses like introduction to programming, symbolic artificial intelligence, mathematical logic, data structures and so much more. My experience involve mostly constraint programming, first-order logic, multi-paradigm programming and declarative languages (e.g. PROLOG, PICAT, Haskell, Minizinc, C/C++, Python, etc.). Now, I wish to start a new chapter of my career and I'm looking to shift towards helping solving industry-oriented real-world problems using the knowledge and expertise I acquired throughout my life. Please, check the note about my availability at the end of this CV.

### PERSONAL DETAILS

Address Rua: Ex-Combatentes 125 – Casa E3 – 89.221-103 – Joinville – SC

Country Brazil

Phone (+55) 47 99245 1825

Mails ccs1664@gmail.com - ccs1664@yahoo.com Site https://claudiocesar.wordpress.com/ GitHub https://github.com/claudiosa/

## **EDUCATION**

#### Post-doctorate Research (sabbatical year)

2010 - 2010

Université d'Auvergne – Clermont Ferrand – Aurvegne – France

Grant support from Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel (CAPES – Brazil). Subject: theoretical aspects of Constraint Programming.

### Doctor in Science 1992–1997

Aeronautics Institute of Technology (ITA) – São José dos Campos – SP – Brazil

Grant support from Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel (CAPES – Brazil) and Federal University of Alagoas.

Subject: Artificial Intelligence and Theory of Computation.

#### Master in Science 1982–1987

Federal University of Paraíba (UFPb) – Campina Grande – PB – Brazil Subject: Performance Network.

#### Bachelor in Electrical Engineering

1977-1981

 $Santa\ Catarina\ State\ University\ (UDESC)\ -\ Joinville\ -\ SC\ -\ Brazil$ 

Concentration: Electronic and Telecommunication

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

WhatsTV current

https://www.whatstv.com.br/

I had worked technical support for users of our product. As well as, I have been contact/tests with many Web technologies.

 $\mathbf{Upwork} \\ \mathbf{2019} - \mathbf{2021}$ 

https://www.upwork.com/ - Eventually, on-demand.

I had worked as a programmer in languages listed below, my profile is found in: https://www.upwork.com/o/profiles/users/~019017be3783b12815/. I am putting in hold on.

### Modal Institute (Instituto Modal)

2020 - 2020

Full-time - https://institutomodal.org.br/

I worked for one month in a project with Prolog, consulting, training a team, and developer.

#### Lecturer in Computer Science

1986 - 2019

Many universities in Brazil as Computer Science professor

During this period I taught and research in many universities in Brazil. The CNPq site brings a detailed CV about myself in: http://lattes.cnpq.br/2946250323814779 This CV provided is strictly with an academic view. It is omitted due its size.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Windows, Linux System:

Programming:  $C++(\star\star)$ ,  $C(\star\star\star)$ , Python  $(\star\star\star)$ , Picat  $(\star\star\star\star\star)$ , Prolog  $(\star\star\star\star\star)$ ,

ASP  $(\star\star\star)$ , Haskell  $(\star\star\star)$ , BASH  $(\star\star)$  where a  $\star$ : represents domain or fluency

Solvers: Minizing, OPL, OR-TOOLS and Answer Set Programming – ASP

Editors: LIBREOFFICE, LATEX, EMACS

### **SKILLS**

- Symbolic AI
- Declarative Languages
- Constraint Programming
- Modelling in Combinatorial Problems

## **LANGUAGES**

Languages: Portuguese (mother tongue)

English (fluent)

French (fluent – except to write) Spanish (good – except to write)

### **AVAILABILITY**

Due my many reasons, at this moment, I am interested in a part-time job and remote. So, the consulting tasks has been more suitable for me. But, in the future, a changing country or city can be evaluated.

# **LEISURES**

Swimming: my age!

Active swimmer in open water competitions in Brazil – level advanced in according

My Youtube channel:

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdXNTAs1Sv7ARPr-TuViEUA